A Guide to the University of Virginia, Student Council, Office Administrative Files, 1968-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia, Student Council, Office Administrative Files 1968-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-23/2/4.891
This collection consists of ca. 4000 items, which are ca. 5 shelf feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection is an archival transfer from the Student Council, care of Ms Mary Ferrate, 109 Peabody Hall University of Virginia on 1989 July 17.
Scope and Content Information
Working papers of Council including allocation requests by individual groups, minutes and material regarding Birdwood.
Topics include: Amateur Radio Club, Anthropology Association, Beta Alpha Phi, Black American Law Students Association, Blue Ridge Mountain Rescue Group, Cavalier Pep Band, Corks and Curls, Day Care, Democratic Socialist Club, Echols Scholors, Egyptian Students Association, Food and Transportation, Grass Roots, Hunger Week (and Other Charitable Projects), Jazz Ensemble, Madison House, Parking and Transportation, Safety and Security, Sorority Recognition, United Way Campaign, Volunteer Committee, Wine Taster's Society, Youth Services, and various Appeals and Hearings and Newspaper Clippings.
Contents List
- Series I: Topical Files
  - The Ad Hoc Caroling Committee of the University of Virginia 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Academics 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Akiba 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol Awareness Week 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Alpha Phi Omega Service Frat. 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Alpha Pi Sorority 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Amateur Radio Club 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Aeronautic and Astronautics 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Chemical Engineers 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - American Nuclear Society, UVa Student Branch of 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Angel Flight 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Anthropology Association 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Applications 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Appropriations Letters (Groups) 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Architectural Historians, Society of 1968-1977 (Box 1)
  - Art Majors Association 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Asian Studies Club 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Association for Women's Concerns 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Association of Education Stud. 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Association of Residential Councils 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Auditing Committee 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Ballet 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - The Barrister, Inc. 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Bernard Cornfeld Pre-Business Squad 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Beta Alpha Phi 1972-1977 (Box 1)
  - Birdwood: Ad Hoc Committee 1978 (Box 1)
  - Applications to Birdwood Committee 1979 (Box 1)
  - Birdwood Building Committee 1972-1978 (Box 1)
  - Birdwood -Correspondence 1978 (Box 1)
  - Birdwood Housing 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Birdwood Media Articles 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Black American Law Students Assoc. 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - Black Concerns 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Black Concerns Coordinator 1982 (Box 2)
  - Black Student Alliance 1973-1976 (Box 2)
  - Black Voices 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Blue Ridge Mountain Rescue Group 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - Board of Visitors 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Board of Visitors Correspondence 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - BOV - Legislation 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - The Book Exchange 1983 (Box 2)
  - Botany Club 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - Bowling Club 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Boxing Club 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Budget - SC 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Business Forum 1963-1977 (Box 2)
  - Campus Assoc. for Research and Enlightenment (CARE) 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Cavalier Pep Band 1970-1976 (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville Continental Walk Committee 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville United Soccer Club 1975-1978 (Box 2)
  - Chess Club 1969-1977 (Box 2)
  - Chinese Student Assoc. 1970-1976 (Box 2)
  - Club Sports Policy 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Commerce Council 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Committee Budgets 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Committee Budget Requests 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Committee Chairmen/Reps 1981-1983 (Box 2)
  - Communications-Admissions; Contact; Liaison; Newsletter; Media Coordinator 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Committee for a Social Movements Collection 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Complaints Prior to Information/Complaint File 1977-1979 (Box 2)
  - Constitution and By-Laws 1969-1983 (Box 3)
  - Corks and Curls 1956-1977 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence 1978 (Box 3)
  - Housing Correspondence1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence from SC Officers 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Officer Correspondence1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Counselors Committee on Human Sexuality 1974-1977 (Box 3)
  - The Coupon Book 1981 (Box 3)
  - Course Evaluation Book 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - The Darden School Student Government Association 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - Day Care 1978-1982 (Box 3)
  - Day Care Center 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - The Declaration 1972-1975 (Box 3)
  - Delta Kappa Sorority 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Democratic Socialist Club 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - The Discordian Society 1974-1977 (Box 3)
  - Dockets and Releases 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - Duplicate Bridge Club 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - Echols Scholars 1979 (Box 3)
  - Economics Club 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - Egyptian Students Assoc. 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Elections 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Elections Cmt 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Elections Committee 1983-1985 (Box 4)
  - Elections Rules Committee n.d. (Box 4)
  - Engineering Council 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - English Club - Graduate 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - English Club - Undergraduate 1976 (Box 4)
  - The Escort Service 1982 (Box 4)
  - Essays in History 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Evangelical Students' Forum 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Experimental University 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Committee - Academic Legislation 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Fall Registration 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Fencing Club 1974-1976 (Box 4)
  - Film Production Union 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Folk Dance Club 1973 (Box 4)
  - Food and Transportation 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Foreign Studies CMT 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Gamma Pi Chapter Eta Kappa Nu Association 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - The German Club, UVa 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Glee Club 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Goals - Reports, Committee (1981)1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - Graduate Economics Club 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Grass Roots 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Grotto 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Guest Speakers - Student Council 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Halsey Hall Closing 1978-1980 (Box 4)
  - Handicapped Concerns Coordinator 1982 (Box 4)
  - Historical Simulation Society 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - History Club 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Honor Referendum Committee 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - The Hook Book 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Hunger Week (and Other Charitable Projects) 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Housing 1981 (Box 4)
  - Housing Sites 1980 (Box 4)
  - Ice Hockey Club 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - IEEE - Institute of Electrical & Electronic Engineers 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - India Association 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Insurance Correspondence 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Intercom 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - International Club 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - International Folk-Dancing Club 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - International Relations Organization 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - International Students 1981 (Box 4)
  - International Students Coordinator 1983 (Box 4)
  - Italian Club 1972-1977 (Box 4)
  - Jazz Ensemble 1974-1977 (Box 5)
  - Jefferson Literary and Debating Society 1972-1978 (Box 5)
  - John Bassett Moore Society of International Law 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Kappa Alpha Psi 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Kappa Gamma Fraternity 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Kiosks 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Lambda Gamma of Chi Omega Fraternity 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Lambeth Questionnaire 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Law Review 1973-1977 (Box 5)
  - Lease Dates 1979 (Box 5)
  - Legal Assistance Society 1975-1977 (Box 5)
  - Legal Environment Group 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Legislative 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Legislative Committee 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Letters - Congratulatory, Encouragement, Etc. (1981) 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - LOKI 1975-1977 (Box 5)
  - Madison House 1974-1977 (Box 5)
  - Mailouts-Summer 1981-1984, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - McIntire School of Commerce 1971-1975 (Box 5)
  - McIntire School of Commerce Collegiate Chapter of American Marketing Association 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Media Coordinator 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Student Council 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Modern Dance Club 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Mulholland Society 1967-1976 (Box 5)
  - Muntu Fine Arts Guild 1974-1976 (Box 5)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW) 1974-1976 (Box 5)
  - Newsletter Committee 1982 (Box 5)
  - Nichiren Shoshu Academy 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - NROTC Honor Guard 1975-1977 (Box 5)
  - Office Forms - Requests for Equipment, Repair, etc. 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Organization Letters - Requests for info reg. Recognition 1982 (Box 5)
  - Office Memorandums 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Office Memos-Records 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Office Procedures 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Omega Chi Sorority 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Opportunity Consultants, Inc. 1975-1977 (Box 5)
  - Organization Recognized by SC 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Organizations Recognized by Student Council 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Orientation - Fall & Spring 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Orientation - Spring & Fall 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Outing Club 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Outposts 1980 (Box 6)
  - Parking & Transportation Problems 1981 (Box 6)
  - Pavilion XI Study Committee 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Petition/Budget Request Forms 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Phi Sigma Biology Honor Society 1974-1977 (Box 6)
  - Philosophy Club 1975-1977 (Box 6)
  - Physics Society 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Poetry Team 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Polo Club 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Post Conviction Assistance Project 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Professional Young Republican Club 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Public Administration Group 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Radical Feminist Union 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Recognition Process 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Recognized Organizations and Correspondence Pertaining Thereto 1976-1983 (Box 6)
  - Reports - President's, etc. 1982 (Box 6)
  - Registration Tables 1982 (Box 6)
  - Residential Colleges 1972-1979 (Box 6)
  - Resolutions (1980) 1981-1982 (1983) (Box 6)
  - Riding Club 1971-1977 (Box 6)
  - Rifle and Pistol Club 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - [Rivanna]-To Be Recognized 1974-1977 (Box 6)
  - Safety & Security 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Safety & Security Committee 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Sailing Association 1971-1977 (Box 6)
  - Santa Claus Society 1976-1977 (Box 6)
  - Sawan-Kirpal Mission 1976-1977 (Box 6)
  - Scuba Club 1969-1976 (Box 6)
  - S.D.C. - Current 1979 (Box 6)
  - S.D.C. - Facts About Membership 1974-1981 (Box 6)
  - S.D.C. - Minutes/Memos 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Self-Awareness Club 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Seven Sour Sippers Society 1969-1976 (Box 7)
  - Shorin Ryu Karate Assoc. 1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - Ski Club 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Skydiving Club 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - Slavic Club 1968-1975 (Box 7)
  - Social Movements Collection 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Softball Club 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - Sorority Recognition 1977-1978 (Box 7)
  - Southeastern Review 1973-1977 (Box 7)
  - Spanish Club (El Club Hispanico) 1973-1976 (Box 7)
  - Squash Club 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Startrek Coterie 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Student Council Membership 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Student Leaders 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Student Legal Forum 1974-1977 (Box 7)
  - Student Nurses Association of Virginia 1968-1977 (Box 7)
  - Student on BOV Issue 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Student Planning Organization 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Student Services CMT 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Student for a Free Society 1972-1976 (Box 7)
  - Students for an Effective Honor System 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Symphonic Band 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - Synchronized Swimming Club 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - Table Tennis Club 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - TASC 1982 (Box 7)
  - Tax Assistance Program 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - Tax Assistance Program of C'ville 1972-1976 (Box 7)
  - University Escort Service 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - United Way Campaign 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - United Way Committee 1983 (Box 7)
  - University Committees 1981-1983 (Box 7)
  - University Committees Committee 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - University Family Housing Association 1950-1975 (Box 7)
  - University Republican Club 1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - University of Virginia Democrats 1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - The Virginia Debaters 1968-1977 (Box 7)
  - Virginia Law Weekly 1961-1977 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Legislative Service 1971-1976 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Organization for Women's Sports 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Players 1975-1977 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Public Interest Research Group Organizing Comm. 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Students for Community Health 1973 (Box 8)
  - Volleyball Club 1974-1977 (Box 8)
  - Volunteers Committee n.d. (Box 8)
  - Windlass 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Wine Taster's Society 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Women's Chorus 1974-1977 (Box 8)
  - Women's Concerns Coordinator 1982-1983 (Box 8)
  - Women's Lacrosse Club 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Women's Track Club 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - WTJU-FM - Station #1 Humphreys 1974-1977 (Box 8)
  - WUVA Incorporated 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Yearly Housing Booklet 1977-1981 (Box 8)
  - Young Americans for Freedom (YAF) 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Young Life Campaign 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Young People for President Ford 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Youth Services n.d. (Box 8)
  - Zeta Delta Local Sorority 1976-1977 (Box 8)
- Series II: Allocations/Appropriations
  - [Allocation] - Guidelines n.d. (Box 8)
  - Allocation List 1975-1977, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Allocations 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Allocations - Fall 1977 (Box 8)
  - Allocations - Spring 1977 (Box 8)
  - Allocations - Spring 1980-1981 (Box 8)
  - Appropriations - Fall Packet 1977 (Box 8)
  - Appropriations - Final Report 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Appropriations - Personal 1979 (Box 8)
  - Approp - To File 1975 (Box 8)
  - Released Monies 1975-1978, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - SAF Budget Request 1976-1977 (Box 8)
- Series III: Appeals/Hearings
  - Appeals - Fall 1975 (Box 9)
  - Appeals - Spring 1974-1978, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Appropriations Appeals - Spring 1977 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence [Appropriations] (1974) 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence [Appropriations] 1978 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence - SAF 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence - Sandy Williams 1976 (Box 9)
  - Fraternities and Sororities 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Hearings - Fall 1975 (Box 9)
  - Hearings - Spring 1975-1976, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Hearings - Spring 1978 (Box 9)
  - Majority Opinions of the SAF - Spring 1977 (Box 9)
  - Minutes from Appropriations Hearings 1977 Mar (Box 9)
  - Music Organizations 1976-1976 (Box 9)
  - Publications 1971-1976 (Box 9)
  - Record of Members in Funded Organizations n.d. (Box 9)
  - Unwritten Rules 1979 (Box 9)
  - The Va. Weekly Appeal 1977 (Box 9)
  - The Virginia Law Review 1974-1977 (Box 9)
  - News Paper Clippings
  - Newspaper Clippings 1977-1978 (Box 10)
  - Newspaper File - Ads - Housing 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Newspaper File - IFC-United Way 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1974-1976 (Box 11)
- Series IV: Minutes
  - Minutes 1969-1971, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Minutes - Incomplete 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - Minutes 1973-1975 (Box 11)
  - Committee Meetings - Minutes and Resolutions 1974-1976 (Box 11)
  - Minutes 1975-1980, 6 folders (Box 12)
  - Pre-Minutes 1979-1981 (Box 12)
  - Agenda/ Minutes1982-1983 (Box 12)